Mahed Abroshan

E-mail Address: mabroshan@turing.ac.uk

The Alan Turing Institute, British Library, 96 Euston Rd, London, UK

Phone Number: (+44) 7565860620

Overview:

I am currently a postdoctoral researcher at Alan Turing Institute working on trustworthy machine learning and applying ML in healthcare. My strong background in mathematics (demonstrated in my dual undergraduate degree and my success in national and international mathematics competition) along with my extensive experience in information theory, equipped me well for the research in machine learning. I am passionate about problem solving and research on fundamental problems with real-life impact.

Employment

The Alan Turing Institute

Postdoctoral Research Associate

Project: Learning machine for healthcare and criminal justice program

PIs: Prof. Sir Alan Wilson and Prof. Mihaela van der Schaar

University of Cambridge

Postdoctoral researcher

Department of Applied Mathematics and Theoretical Physics

Project: Machine learning for healthcare

PI: Prof. Mihaela van der Schaar

London, UK October 2019-Present

Cambridge, UK *July 2019- March 2020*

Education

• University of Cambridge, St. Edmund's College

Ph.D. in Engineering

Supervisors: Albert Guillén i Fàbregas and Ramji Venkataramanan Thesis: Insertion/Deletion Channels and File Synchronization Problem Cambridge, UK
Oct. 2015 – July 2019

Tehran, Iran *Sept.* 2013 – Aug. 2015

• Sharif University of Technology

M.Sc. Communication systems

Thesis: Zero Error Coordination (Supervisor: Amin Gohari)

GPA: 18.6/20

Sharif University of Technology

B.Sc. Pure Mathematics (As the second major)

Tehran, Iran

Sept. 2010 – Jun. 2014

Sharif University of Technology

B.Sc. Electrical Engineering Overall B.Sc. GPA: 18.09/20 Tehran, Iran

Sept. 2009 – Jun. 2013

Awards & Honors

- Cambridge Trust and Trinity College-Henry Barlow Scholarships, (2015-2019)
- Third Prize in International Mathematics Competition for university students (IMC), Bulgaria, July 2014
- **Departmental Scholarship** funded by European Research Council Grant, Department of Engineering, University of Cambridge (2015-2019)
- Entering the M.Sc. program as an exceptional talented student bypassing the entrance exam
- Santander Mobility Grant (June 2019) and ISIT travel awards (2017, 2018, and 2019)
- Silver Medalist in Iranian Mathematical Society Collegiate Competition, May 2014
- Grant for Undergraduate Studies Iranian National Elite Foundation, 2009 to 2015
- Gold Medalist of the Iranian National Mathematics Olympiad, 2008
- Silver Medalist of the Iranian National Mathematics Olympiad, 2007

Publications

Journal papers:

- M. Abroshan, K. Yip, C. Tekin, M. van der Schaar, "Conservative Policy Construction Using Variational Autoencoders for Logged Data with Missing Values" IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems (2022)
- M. Abroshan, R. Venkataramanan, A. Guillén i Fàbregas, "Multilayer Codes for Synchronization from Deletions and Insertions" IEEE Transactions on Information Theory (2020)
- M. Abroshan, A. M. Alaa, O. Rayner, M. van der Schaar, "Opportunities for machine learning to transform care for people with cystic fibrosis" (editorial) Journal of Cystic Fibrosis (2020)
- M. Abroshan, R. Venkataramanan, A. Guillén i Fàbregas, "Coding for Segmented Edit Channels" IEEE Transactions on Information Theory (2018)

Conference papers:

- (Under review) M. Abroshan, S. Mishra, M.M. Khalili, "A Memetic algorithm for Interpreting Blackboxes Using Primitive Functions"
- (Under review) M.M. Khalili, X. Zhang, M. Abroshan, I. Vakilinia, "Non-convex Optimization for Learning a Fair Predictor under Equalized Loss Fairness Constraint"
- (Accepted) M. Abroshan*, G. Aminian*, M.M. Khalili, M. Rodrigues, "A Theoretical-Inspired Method for Semi-supervised Learning under Covariate-shift", AISTAT 2022 (* equal contribution)
- M.M. Khalili, X. Zhang, M. Abroshan, "Fair Sequential Selection Using Supervised Learning Models"
 Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems, Neurips 2021

- M.M. Khalili, X. Zhang, M. Abroshan, S. Sojoudi, "Improving Fairness and Privacy in Selection Problems" Association for the Advancement of Artificial Intelligence AAAI 2021
- M. Abroshan, R. Venkataramanan, L. Dolecek, A. Guillén i Fàbregas, "Coding for Deletion Channels with Multiple Traces" IEEE International Symposium on Information Theory 2019
- M. Abroshan, R. Venkataramanan, A. Guillén i Fàbregas, "Efficient Systematic Encoding of Non-Binary VT codes" IEEE International Symposium on Information Theory 2018
- M. Abroshan, R. Venkataramanan, A. Guillén i Fàbregas, "Codes for Channels with Segmented Edit" IEEE International Symposium on Information Theory 2017
- M. Abroshan, R. Venkataramanan, A. Guillén i Fàbregas, "Multilayer Codes for Synchronization from Deletions" IEEE Information Theory Workshop 2017, http://arxiv.org/abs/1705.06670
- M. Abroshan, A. A. Gohari, S. Jaggi, "Zero Error Coordination" IEEE Information Theory Workshop 2015, https://arxiv.org/pdf/1505.01110v1.pdf

Research visits and Internships

- Multiple deletion channels with application in DNA storage
 Research visit to Department of Electrical Engineering, University of California Los Angeles (UCLA),
 hosted by Prof. Lara Dolecek (June July 2018). One paper published.
- Codes for Deletion channels

Research visits and collaboration with information theory and coding group at UPF Barcelona, Spring 2016.

Coordination Problem in Networks

Internship at Institute of Network Coding, Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK), hosted by Prof. Sidharth Jaggi (Feb 2014 – Jul 2015). One paper published.

Teaching Experience

- Supervising **Inference**, University of Cambridge, Lent term 2018
- Supervising Signals and Systems, University of Cambridge, Michaelmas 2017
- Supervising Information Theory and Coding, U of Cambridge, Michaelmas 2016 and 2017
- Demonstrating **Data Transmission Lab**, University of Cambridge, Lent 2016,17,18
- Teaching Assistant for **Probability and Statistics**, Sharif University of Technology, Fall 2014
- Teaching Geometry for Preparation of National Mathematics Olympiad Team, Fall 2010
- Teaching Combinatorics and Graph Theory in Allameh Amini High School, Fall 2010

Programming skills

• Python (pytorch, tensorflow, sklearn), MATLAB, C++

References

• Dr. Albert Guillén i Fàbregas

Department of Engineering, University of Cambridge, Email: guillen@ieee.org

• Dr. Ramji Venkataramanan

Department of Engineering, University of Cambridge, Email: ramji.v@eng.cam.ac.uk

• Professor Sir Alan Wilson

Director of Special Projects, Alan Turing Institute, and honorary professor at UCL, Email: awilson@turing.ac.uk